+1 (236) 868-7483 Vancouver, BC shn.khorsandi@gmail.com

Shayan Khorsandi

Full Stack Developer

Portfolio: abradat.github.io/portfolio github.com/abradat linkedin.com/in/sh-khorsandi

Full stack developer with 3+ years of professional experience working on three enterprise banking projects based on microservices architecture. Enthusiastic about exploring new fields with more than three years of research experience and three publications.

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2022 — June 2022 **Application Developer**

Dyne Technologies Inc.

Vancouver, BC

- Mobile application development using Flutter framework for iOS and Android platforms.
- Redesigned the whole routing and dependency management of the mobile app to reduce memory usage.
- Implemented new features, including integration with Instagram and tutorial for onboarding users.
- Redesigned and standardized REST API endpoints on the server-side for increasing performance and readability.

Software Engineer Informatics Services Corporation (ISC) May 2018 — Aug 2021

Tehran, Iran

- Developed core services of the Central Bank of Iran (CBI). Member of Central Securities Depository (CSD) and Iranian Instant Payment (IIP) projects, providing services to all 30 banks of the country.
- Developed backend services through Spring Boot and Spring frameworks based on microservices architecture.
- Implemented microservices patterns, including Saga Transaction pattern, API Gateway using Spring Cloud Gateway and Zuul, securing services based on OpenID Connect, messaging/streaming using Apache Kafka and IBM MQ, and distributed log tracing using Zipkin and ELK stack for the CSD project.
- Developed a Socket.IO client based on Spring Boot for communication between customer banks and CBI for the IIP project.
- Developed dashboard monitoring and management applications via Angular framework. Implemented a terminal for real-time communication between an Angular application and server's command line using WebSocket and Xterm.js for the IIP project.
- Containerized applications using Docker and used Jenkins for CI/CD.

Research Assistant, Bio-Inspired System Design Lab

Jun 2016 — Feb 2020

Tehran, Iran

- Amirkabir University of Technology · Implemented a method for predicting a ball's trajectory in humanoid robots based on the combination of k-NN Regression and Auto Regression in real and Gazebo simulator environments.
- Developed Motion Editor application for monitoring Herkulex servo motors and motion generation using PyQt and Arduino.
- Developed Walk Tuner and Offset Tuner applications for walking calibration based on PyQt and Arduino.

SKILLS

Languages Proficient in: Java, Python, C/C++, Typescript, Dart

Familiar with: C#, Go, Swift, Javascript, Solidity, Bash

Spring Boot, Spring, Angular, Vue.js, Flutter, Django, Flask, Beego Frameworks

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins

Tools Git, SVN, Maven, Apache Kafka, IBM MQ, ELK Stack, Redis

Database Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Platforms AWS

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Central Securities Depository (CSD) V2 —

☐ Documentation

May 2020 — Aug 2021

Central Bank of Iran's new CSD system. Implemented based on microservices architecture with completely redesigned backend services and frontend Angular dashboard.

Iranian Instant Payment (IIP) —
☐ Documentation

Aug 2019 — Aug 2021

IIP is Central Bank of Iran's latest inter-bank payment system. Implemented based on the microservices architecture.

Reddit Analysis— C Source Code | Documentation

Winter 2021

Application for crawling subreddit posts from Reddit website using Scrapy and analyzing them using SciPy and Stanford CoreNLP. News Crawler — ○ Source Code | Documentation

Web application for crawling the latest news from CNN website through Selenium and latest tweets through Twitter API about PS5 console. Tweets' sentiments are extracted using Stanford CoreNLP for labeling and presentation in the Angular application.

Linux kernel module for hooking read and write system calls using ftrace and performing encrypt/decrypt actions with ROT13. For a comprehensive list of my projects please visit my website or my github.

EDUCATION

Master of Digital Media, Simon Fraser University, Canada

(GPA: 4.0/4.33), Sep 2021 — Present

Accredited and awarded by four leading Canadian post-secondary institutions: <u>UBC</u>, <u>SFU</u>, <u>ECUAD</u>, <u>BCIT</u>.

B.Sc. Computer Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Iran

(GPA: 3.72/4.0), Sep 2015 — Mar 2020